# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I'll teach you a common dish
# 凉拌菱角菜
Spicy mustard plant stem salad
# 首先我们准备菱角菜2颗
First, prepare two mustard plant stems
# 同学们菱角菜其实就是制作榨菜的原材料
Mustard plant stem is actually what Chinese pickle, "Zha Cai", is made of
# 然后将其老的经络撕掉备用
Remove the hard part on the surface
# 同学们凉拌的菱角菜必须先晾晒几天
The stems must be aired for several days before being cooked
# 这样才能够轻易地撕下筋膜
This makes removing the surface part much easier
# 然后将菱角菜平刀切成厚片再切成粗丝备用
Then cut the veggies into thick slices and then thick threads
# 嫌麻烦的同学也可以直接切成薄片
If that's too much, you can cut them into thin slices
# 下一步开始初加工
The next step is the pre-processing
# 首先在盆中加入食用盐6克
First, add 6g of salt to the bowl
# 加入白糖4克
Add 4g of sugar
# 加入白醋6克
Add 6g of rice vinegar
# 然后将其抓拌均匀出水30分钟
Then mix them for 30 minutes to remove the water from the veggies
# 30分钟之后捞出挤干水分备用
After 30 minutes, take the veggies out and squeeze out the water
# 下一步开始调味
The next step is to season the veggies
# 碗中加入适量的刀口辣椒面（约5克）
Add some Daokou chili powder to the bowl (around 5g)
# 没有刀口辣椒的同学也可以用普通辣椒面代替
If you don't have Daokou chili powder, you can use any other kind of chili powder
# 碗中加入花椒面1勺（约2克）
Add a teaspoon of ground Sichuan peppercorn to the bowl (around 2g)
# 加入白糖1勺（约2克）
Add a teaspoon of sugar (around 2g)
# 然后搅拌均匀即可装盘上菜
Then mix everything and lay it out in the plate
# 一道香辣爽脆的凉拌菱角菜就制作完成
Now, we've finished making this spicy and refreshing spicy mustard plant stem salad
# 下面开始技术总结
第一，切好的菱角菜必须加入盐糖白醋
刹水，这一步的目的是保证菜品的爽脆
第二，刹好水之后可以不用清洗直接加料凉拌
第三，不喜欢吃辣的同学可以不加辣椒和花椒
只需加入盐和白糖即可
凉拌菱角菜的技术总结完毕
# Now, let's summarize the key techniques:
# First, we need to add the salt. sugar, and rice vinegar mixture to the cutted veggies to remove the water, making sure the final product is refreshing and crispy
# Secondly, we don't need to rinse the veggies after the water removal step
# Thirdly, If you don't like spicy food, you don't need to add chili and peppercorn; salt and sugar will be enough.
# Above are all the techniques for the spicy mustard plant stem salad